<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://cseyda.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cseyda.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Surfstick and internet sharing with networkmanager</title>
      <link>https://cseyda.github.io/post/20160704_surfstick_networkmanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cseyda.github.io/post/20160704_surfstick_networkmanager/</guid>
      <description>Wired internet broke after floodings. To bridge the time till all repairs are finished I received a K4203 SurfStick. Some instructions how to get it to work and share the internet connection follows.
#K4203 SurfStick This stick provides a wireless internet connection through UMTS. In my case it didn&amp;rsquo;t work out of the box. Upon insertion in an USB slot it registered itself as a CD-reader. Apparently USB devices can have different modes of operation and change according to the situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts under linux, a short example</title>
      <link>https://cseyda.github.io/post/20160625_podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cseyda.github.io/post/20160625_podcasts/</guid>
      <description>I recently started listening to podcasts. Intrigued by the usual promises of learning things, gaining perspectives and finding inspiration, there was luckily little friction in finding, getting and hearing them on linux. Only syncing to my mp3-player is a bit of a hassle.
What are podcasts, why should you listen to them and when? Podcasts are modern radio shows.
What internet videos/shows are to TV, podcasts are to radio shows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My article reading and consumption flow</title>
      <link>https://cseyda.github.io/post/20160417_reading_flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cseyda.github.io/post/20160417_reading_flow/</guid>
      <description>It was too much. Articles in bookmarks, open tabs, tab groups, sometimes over different browsers and operating systems and even in my todo list &amp;hellip; This had to to change. A process for reading was needed. First step was to open even more tabs and add more bookmarks. But after some reading how others approach this topic, I got to work uncluttering this mess.
In hindsight, the whole process is pretty obvious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://cseyda.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cseyda.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey!
My name is Christian Seyda.
I am a computer scientist (developer/programmer, tinkerer &amp;amp; thinker) from Germany, living in a small town around Heidelberg.
My interests right now range from Linux and Python, over software/open source, consumer hardware, to productivity and health (nutrition/sports).
Generally thou, I pretty much like to learn about everything new in computer science, software, hardware, other sciences and topics I don&amp;rsquo;t yet know about :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My master&#39;s thesis</title>
      <link>https://cseyda.github.io/post/20131206_masters_thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cseyda.github.io/post/20131206_masters_thesis/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of graph-based and vector-space geographical topic detection Link to the PDF
Abstract The popularity of social networks like Facebook and Twitter, together with media sharing plattforms like Flickr and the ubiquity of modern smart phones and cameras with GPS sensors have lead to a vast amount of data with documents containing locations, text, and even more information. this data can be leveraged to optimise search results, perform targeted advertisement and even help people and authorities in case of nature catastrophes, for example as early warning systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My bachelor&#39;s thesis</title>
      <link>https://cseyda.github.io/post/20110328_bachelors_thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cseyda.github.io/post/20110328_bachelors_thesis/</guid>
      <description>Estimation of Power Consumption of DVFS-Enabled Processors Link to the PDF
Abstract Saving energy is nowadays a critical factor, especially for data centers or high performance clusters which have a power consumption of several mega watts. The simple use of component energy saving mechanisms is not always possible, because this can lead to performance degradation. For this reason, high performance clusters are mainly not using them, even in low utilization phases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>