<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Personal blog of Christian Seyda</title><link href="//cseyda.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//cseyda.github.io/feeds/reading.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//cseyda.github.io/</id><updated>2016-04-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>My article reading and consumption flow</title><link href="//cseyda.github.io/reading-flow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Christian Seyda</name></author><id>tag:cseyda.github.io,2016-04-17:reading-flow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was overwhelmed. Articles in bookmarks, open tabs, tab groups, sometimes over different browsers and operating systems and even in my todo list … This had to to change. A process for reading was needed.
First step was to open even more tabs and add more bookmarks. But after some reading how others approach this topic, I got to work uncluttering this mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, the whole process is pretty obvious. It basically works this way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Articles come in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some are read, some are added to a read-later list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Later, articles from the read-later list are read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My implementation is a little more complex, because I added a research process and wanted to take more notes of what I learned (and because I am a complicated person?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resulting reading flow can be devided into different parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Documents and decisions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually all articles I read either come from the links gathered by looking something up in my browser, or though my feed reader (&lt;a href="https://inoreader.com"&gt;InoReader&lt;/a&gt;). These articles can be roughly divided into three types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;News or otherweise short read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To-do or to-remember&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lenghty article&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short articles can be read as soon as I process them. It usually takes longer to store them for later, and often the relevant tidbit of story is contained in the headline and first paragraph. Unless I deem a short article save-worthy for later, it is read and closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A to-do or to-remember are for example dates I sould keep track of or articles/tutorials outlining some action. They are stored in my prefered todo-list application (&lt;a href="https://wunderlist.com"&gt;Wunderlist&lt;/a&gt;), with date or reminder as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lengthy articles, or topics I feel the urge to check out, are either read or stored, depending if I have the time and desire to readt them right now, or if they apply to the topic I check out. Temporary storage for worked on links are browser tabs (with the chrome extension &lt;a href="https://one-tab.com"&gt;OneTab&lt;/a&gt;), while other links I want to attend later are collected in a read-later service (&lt;a href="https://getpocket.com"&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Actions and storage&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to process the tabs, read-later articles and todos. Todos are automatically processed as they come up, either with a reminder, or as next natural challenge on my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the read-later articles I have regular time-slots. Some freshly brewed black coffee, and then I read what seems the most interessting. If the time is up, the remaining articles have to wait till next time. While reading I try to take notes of the interessting ideas/facts, so I can later recall what it was about. Processed articles are then stored in a bookmarking-service (&lt;a href="https://diigo.com"&gt;Diigo&lt;/a&gt;), together with the notes. Notes can also wander in my wiki, if they contribute or start a new topic worth keeping near me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tabs are closed and used as the topic dictates. References/links and notes are written down in a wiki (&lt;a href="https://zim-wiki.org/"&gt;Zim&lt;/a&gt;). If the subject are worth a broader audience, I intend to write a blog post about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fulltext article storage is something I contemplated about, but decided to be not worth the hassle. Diigo and &lt;a href="https://pinboard.in"&gt;Pinboard&lt;/a&gt; offer fulltext storage, there are solutions for Evernote, and storing locally as file is no problem at all, but I honestly have never really needed it. Just take (clear) enough notes, and consider the link as reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this overview is helpful for someone else. It surely has helped me a lot for a more streamlined reading experience, and therefore more time to read more :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Overview of my reading process" src="//cseyda.github.io/images/reading.png" style="width: 830px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="reading"></category><category term="wiki"></category><category term="bookmark"></category></entry></feed>